快点工作
Let's keep those hammers working.
蓝波
Rambo!
过来吧!
Let's go.
你好吗?强尼
How are you, Johnny?
很好
Good.
没事了
That's all.
强尼 很抱歉让你受这种苦
John, I'm sorry they sent you to such a hellhole.
我了解
I've seen worse.
你己受够了是吗?
Yeah, you have, haven't you...
强尼 我告诉过你 我会帮你的
John, I told you that I'd help you when I could.
你很特别
Are you interested?
你绝不能在未来的五年还待在这
You can't possibly wanna stay here for another five years.
至少我知道站在那里
In here at least, I know where I stand.
先听我说
Just hear me out first.
在这儿有一项任务展开
A covert operation is being geared up in the Far East.
你的名字
Your name
是电脑选中的三人之一
was dug out of computer as one of three most able to complete the mission.
什么任务?
Mission?
再前往越南搜索被俘的人员
Recon for POWs in Nam.
为何现在 为何要我去
Why now? Why me?
从俘虏营中逃出来的人员
The prison camp you escaped from in '71 is the target area.
只有你知道俘虏营所在
Nobody knows that terrain better than you do.
危险性非常高
The risk factor is very high.
你将暂调军部 等任务成功
You'd be temporarily reinstated in the Forces,and if the mission's successful
总统也许会大赦
there may be a presidential pardon.
你有兴趣吗?
You interested?
是的
Yeah.
很好
Good...good. .
我去安排一下
I'll get the necessary clearance
下次我们见面时
The next time we meet,
将是在泰国作战总部
it will be in Thailand with the Special Ops designate who runs the operation.
是的
Yes, Sir.
- 明白了吗 - 是
- All clear? - Yes.
强尼 我要你知道
John, I want you to know that
我是要救你出来的
I did what I could to keep you outta here.
我知道
I know.
长官
Yeah.Sir?
这次会赢吗?
Do we get to win this time?
这次看你的
This time, it's up to you...
《第一滴血2》
没事了
That'll be all.
你好吗?蓝波
How you doin', Rambo? I'm Ericson.
何不去那里
Why don't we make it over to the hangar?
你还是入选者是吗?
You're the chosen one, huh?
你可是使自己够出名了
You made a helluva rep' for yourself in Nam!
总之 我很高兴与你共事
Anyway, I'm glad to be workin' with you.
这里虽不是天堂
This place may not be heaven,
但至少可使你愉快的
but at least you're out of the joint!
他来了
He's here.
- 午安 强尼 - 长官
- Morning, John. - Sir.
这位是摩道少将
This is Marshal Murdock.
他是华盛顿派来指挥这任务的
He's in charge of Special Operations from Wahington.
谢谢你 中校
Thank you, Colonel.
蓝波 我正在等你
Rambo, been looking forward to meeting you.
旅途如何?没问题吧!
How was your trip? No problems?
还好
No.
当然这里天气很热
Except for the damned heat, right?
我不喜欢
Never felt anything like it!
进来 我们谈正事吧!
Come on in, let's get down to business!
我看过你的资料
I was glancing over your files.
真是很有趣
Makes some pretty interesting reading!
蓝波约翰生于47年
Rambo, John J., born 7.6.47,
是亚利桑那印第安与德国人混血
Bowie, Arizona, of Indian-German descent.
真复杂
That's a helluva combination!
在64年加入陆军
Joined the army 8.6.64,
入特种作战部队
accepted special forces,
特长:轻武器
specialization: light weapons.
曾受医疗训练 有医疗士资格
Cross-trained as medic. Helicopter and language qualified.
因为单独力杀59名敌人
59 confirmed kills, 2 silver stars, 4 bronze, 4 Purple Hearts,
获得勋章一枚
distinguished service cross, and Medal of Honor.
你很出风头对不对?
You got around, didn't ya?
蓝波 你可能知道还有一千五百
Rambo, you're probably aware that there's almost 2.500 Americans
美国人
still Missing In Action
在越南失踪
in South-East Asia.
大部分己战死的 家庭会死心
Most of these boys are presumed killed,
但仍有许多
but to the legal families,
美国家庭抱着希望
Congress and lots of Americans, it's still a very emotional issue.
有没有什冰凉的
Gimme something cold, please!
蓝波 你可能不太了解我
Rambo, you certainly don't know as much about me as I do you.
我在66年带过海军陆战队
I've honched with the 2nd Battalion,
第二步兵营
3rd Marines, in Kon Tum in '66.
我损失了不少的好人手
I lost a lot of good men
因此 我知道你们的感受
so I know what you and every vet feels now.
也许政府没照料到
Maybe the government didn't care
也许大众不关心
maybe certain segments of the population didn't care,
但是我会在意的
but my committee cares.
因此大家要知道他们是否健康
So what his commitee needs is exclusive proof that Americans are being held.
首先 我们要把他们救回来
Once done, rest sure we'll get 'em back.
这是我方人员去俘虏营四周
Now, if there's any of our men at this POW target camp,
摄到的地图照片
you'll confirm their presence by taking photographs.
照片
Photographs?
只有照片 任何情况下
Just photographs.
不能跟敌人交手
Under no circumstances are you to engage the enemy.
不是要救他们回来吗?
I'm supposed to leave'em there?
我重覆一次 别跟敌人交手
I repeat: do not engage the enemy.
救出行动
Phase 2, Delta Force assault team
要由翰特中校来处理
led by Colonel Trautman will handle the extraction.
好吗?
Okay?
总之以你的作战经验
Anyway, I'd just like to say that I feel with your participation,
我相信成功率是很高的
this mission has a better than average chance
最好还是冒个险看你是否能完成
to succeed where others have failed.
我一小时候在指挥部见你们
I'll meet you both in the operations center in one hour.
泰国金兰湾起飞在越南山区着陆
From Thailand, across Laos, into the mountains of Vietnam, to the drop zone.
你要从250尺高空上跳下
You'll be flying a ceiling of 250 feet when you bail out.
你会处理吗?
Think you can handle it?
当然
I'll try.
你单身前往
Since you're going in solo,
必须依赖很多你从未用过的设备
you'll have to rely on more equipment than you ever used before.
去用吧!我说的是不要好斗
And use it!What I'm sayin' is don't try the blood-and-guts routine.
用点知识来作战
Let technology do most of the work.
约翰 我要你记住任务重于战争
John, I want you to try to forget the war.Remember the mission.
你己在越南死去了
The old Vietnam's dead.
长官 我是个活人且仍然活着
Sir, I'm alive, it's still alive, ain't it?
你也许不相信 但这一切都为你
You may find this hard to believe, but all this is for you!
这是个萤幕
Besides modern computer devices you can see here,
这是确保你安危的设备
issued every other modern piece of equipment we have to ensure your safety.
蓝波 你会很安全的
Rambo, you can feel totally safe
因为我们有最精良的武器
because we have the most advanced weapons in the world available to us.
最具威力的武器是头脑
I've always believed that the mind's the best weapon.
时代变了
Times change.
对某人而言
For some people.
别因我而打断了 中校
Don't let me interrupt you, Colonel.
本部是由卫星传送资料
Upon insertion, call in to base camp on Transat.
然后由地面人员接收
Then proceed to Point Hawk September to rendezvous with the ground contact:
这就是由你接收
Indigenous agent Co Bao.
他怎么了?
Is he listening?
是由你接收
Indigenous agent Co Bao.
中校
Colonel!
你确定他脑筋正常吗?
Are you sure he's still not unbalanced from the war?
这次任务
We can't afford to have him involved
有如下地狱般的压力
in this mission,he might crack under the pressure in that hell!
蓝波是我看过最好的战争人员
Pressure?Let me just say that Rambo is the best combat vet I've ever seen.
不只有战争武器 也有好的战术脑力
A pure fighting machine with only a desire to win a war that someone else lost.
如果要他死 他会死
If winning means he has to die
没有任何恐惧 没有后悔
he'll die. No fear, no regrets.
还有 对你们有如下地狱
And...one more thing:What you choose to call "Hell",
对他有如他回家了
he calls home!
传命 开动ATU
Stand by!Start A.P.U.!
还有20分钟
D minus 20.
五分钟
D minus 5.
(火药)
你有36小时进出
You got 36 hours to get the hell in and out.
别拖时间好吗?
So don't stop to smell the roses, okay?
发现有麻烦
If you run into any trouble,
立刻跑至指定的山顶
try to get to the hilltop extraction site marked on your map.
准备好了 中校
Ready to roll, Colonel.
- 祝好运 - 谢谢
- Good luck, son. - Thanks.
我们走
Let's go!
还记得摩道少将说他在65年
Remember Murdock said he'd been with the 2nd Battalion,
指挥过陆战队吗?
third Marines in Kon Tum in '66?
恩
Yeah.
第9营人员全阵亡了
The 2nd Battalion was at Kud Sank.
你是我唯一信任的人
You're the only one I trust.
你想他会找到人吗?
Think he'll find someone?
他一定会找到俘虏的
POWs? Doubtful.
这是为了令人满意
But there's people to satisfy,
我为何要回答
questions that have to be answered.
你说的口气很冷淡
You don't sound too emotional about it...
不是我的战争 中校
It wasn't my war, Colonel.
这是你擦干净的时候
I'm just here to clean up the mess!
地上的联络员说他们在等待飞机 还有一分钟下降
AWACS two-five has acquired.They're holding timeline.
知道了 完毕
Affirmative, Wolf Den. Over.
又回地狱了 各位
Back in the badlands, my man!
准备 就位
Stand by your position!
15秒钟跳下
Insertion in 15 seconds.
到时候了
Partytime!
五秒
Five seconds!
四
Four...
三
Three...
约翰 跳下
Two...Jumper away.
天啊!怎么了
Shit, what's happening?
钩住了 他被吊着
A turbulence! He's hung up!
我们要把他割断才行
He'll be torn apart!
紧急事件 他吊住了
Condition Red! He's hung up!
- 什么意思? - 发生什么事情了?
- What do you mean he's hung up? - What's happening?
他卡住了!
He's being dragged!
我们把他割断
Lifer cut him loose!
不行啊
I can't free him!
快停止任务实施
Ericson, abort the mission! Pull out.
如果不分开会害死他的
That'll kill him! He'll be torn apart!
他在割断了
He's cutting away his equipment.
他出去了
He's out!
我是龙火一号 收到吗?
Come in here, this is Dragonfly one. Do you read me, over?
龙火一号 我收到了
Dragonfly one, come in, I read you.
有没有照到任务相片
Any visual bearing by flares?
没有 我们什么也看不见
Negative. We didn't see anything.
我想目前只有停止任务
Maybe the smartest thing to do is to abort the mission right now
以免发现太多的后遗症
before there's any more complications.
谁还能在这种情况下生存
I mean who could've survived something like that?
现在来说还过早
He deserves the benefit of the doubt.
他有36小时出完任务
He's got 36 hours to complete the mission,
并到指定地点
and reach the extraction point.
我们都欠他
We owe him that.
当然是的
Of course, we do!
但了解一点吧!
But understand something now:
36小时要作完一切
In 36 hours, we pull out!
蓝波
Rambo!
没想到是女人吧!
You did not expect a woman, no?
我们走吧!
We'd better go.
去河里
We go to river.
为什么来的这么晚
How come you so late?
我被吊住了
Got hung up.
必须坐船 一路上都不安全的
I have arranged boat to take us down river. Old ways not safe.
你从老远来要找俘虏营
You come a long way,Rambo, to see empty camp.
海盗用这些吗?
You're using pirates?
这是河的下游 必须有小艇来警戒
Best way down river.Not get army suspicious.
炸弹在那里?
What about patrol boats?
俄制
Russian.
蓝波 要吃吗?
Rambo!Want to eat?
还是等一下
Maybe later.
你何时开始这任务的
How you get into this?
说来话长
It's a long story.
也花了够久了
Long ride.
在我离开特战部队后
Well...after I left the Special Forces, I...
我就退后了
...moved around a lot.
你为何离开陆军
Why you leave army?
我回美国
I...came back to the States,
发现了另一场战争在持续着
and found another war going on.
什么战争
What war?
有点像静态的战争
Kind of like a quiet war.
是种反对返乡士兵的战争
A war against...all the soldiers returning.
这种战争是赢不了的
It's the kind of war you don't win.
这是我的问题
It's...It's my problem.
你呢?你如何进入这事的
How about you? How did you get into it?
我父亲是情报员
My father worked for intelligence agency.
他死后 我取代他的位置
He killed, and I take his place.
死了太多人 到处都是死人
There's too much death here.Death everywhere.
我只想活下去 蓝波
I just want to live, Rambo.
也许可以去美国过着安静的生活
Maybe go America! Live the quiet life.
你要什么?
What you want?
赢及生存
To win...to survive...
这是你生存的理由这里仍有战争
Not so easy to survive. Still war here.
生存的战争一定会成为战争的
To survive a war, you gotta become war.
因此他们才选你 因你好战吗
That why they pick you? Because you like to fight?
我可以舍身
I am expendable.
舍身是什意思?
Expendable?What mean "expendable"?
就好像有人请你参加派对
It's like......someone invites you to a party
你没出现
and you don't show up
其实也没关系
it doesn't really matter.
这是什么?
What's this?
会给我带来好运
It bring me good luck.
什么替你带来好运
What bring you good luck?
我想是这个
I guess this.
没消息 再多连联络几次
No further report.
我要去救出他
I want to go up with the extraction team at dawn.
- 否决  - 否决?
- Denied. - Denied?
这是冒不必要的危险
It's an unnecessary risk.
我们有程序的
We have a schedule to keep.
管他的 我们还不知他是否活着
For Who?! We don't even know if Rambo's alive!
答案是反对
The odds are against it.
你说我们照计行事
You said we'd go through as planned.
好吧!你要作下去 会的
Okay, if you want to go through with it, we will.
中校 将要加入攻击组
The Colonel's gonna be joining the extraction team.
你真是个好人 翰特
You're a damned good man, Trautman!
看 是个大帐蓬
See? Camp empty.
我走近点看
We move closer.
村子来的妓女
Cyclo-girl whore from village.
来吧!
Come on!
怎么了
What is it?
弓箭 没声音的
A bow. No sound.
你不能进去 你不是要照相吗?
You not going in there.But I thought you're supposed only to take pictures!
那命令呢?
What about orders?
没有命令
No more orders, Co.
我是来帮你的
I've come to get you out.
不要出声
Don't talk.
- 就在那里 - 我会回来的
- There are others. - I'll be back.
走吧!
GO
你没事吧!
Fine?
我们走
Let's go!
可以走了
You have clearance.
一小时要完成行动
Minus one hour to extraction.
希望不会浪费燃料
I hope for his sake we're not just wasting fuel...
我们走吧!
Let's get moving!
还好你来了
A good thing you came when you did.
怎么说
Why is that?
那探索经常移动
They move us around a lot, to harvest crops.
我在那里才一星期
Only been there a week.
就是你在集中营的时候
When was the last time you were in that camp?
是的 一年前
A year...yeah.
今年是几年
What year is it, anyway?
一九八五年
1985.
集中营应该是没人的
Camp supposed to be empty.
应该是
Yeah, supposed to be...
来
Come on!
他们很快会沿河追来的
L.Z. two klicks up river.
这是怎么回事
What has happened?
你们被出卖了
We've been sold out.
混蛋
You bastard!
快走
All right, jump!
我要和他们打
I fight!
快走
Jump! Go on!
快冲过来了
The gunboat!
约翰!
Jump!
我们成功了 蓝波
You made it, Rambo!
好了 我们要继续走
C'mon! You take this. We go on from here.
我要留到最后
It better I stay to end.
这是最后了
This is the end.
我们走
Go on, let's go!
蓝波
Rambo!
你不是牺牲品
You not expendable.
中校 还有三分钟
Colonel, 3 minutes.
那是蓝波
That's Rambo!
天啊!他找到了
Christ, he's found one!
司令部 蓝波找到我们的人了
Relay the command.Rambo's found one of ours!
恐龙号地勤人员报告
Mr Murdock, Dragonfly reports that ground crew
找到一个美军战俘
has what appears to be an American POW with them.
你说什么?
What did you say???
他找到我们的人了
They've got one of ours!
他老给我们找麻烦
This station is now on Condition Bravo. Harrison, Meyers, Goodell, out!
电讯留下 其他的人出去
Everybody out!
快走
Come on, move!
这是优先紧急事件
Go to your COMINT priority frequency!
把麦克风给我
Gimme the mike!
恐龙号这里是教练一号有命令
Dragonfly, this is Coach 1. This is an Alpha-Kilo-Victor command priority.
我要你立刻停止执行命令
I want you to abort the mission immediately!
我再说一次 撤回命令
I say again, this is a recall. Confirm. Over.
再说一次 教练一号
Say it again, coach 1, say it again.
我要你中止行动
I'm tellin' you to abort!
中校 我们奉命在接人以前中止行动
Colonel!I've been ordered to abort before pick-up!
雷达 我们正看到他们
Murdock, Murdock, for Christ sake, we've got 'em in sight!
你听到了吗?
Murdock, do you read?
我们要下去
We're going down!
你那儿也不去
You're not going anywhere.
你们这些该死的佣兵
You goddamned mercenaries!
下面有人是我们的人
There's men down there! OUR men!
不!是你的人
No, your men.
不要充英雄
Don't be a hero.
中校
Colonel!
下来
Don't leave!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你知道你作了什么吗?
Do you know what the hell you've done?
别一副无辜的样子你早就怀疑
Don't act so innocent, Colonel!You had your suspicions
如果如此 你也算是共犯
and if you suspected then, you're sort of an accessory, aren't you?
我从未相信过你 太保
Don't ever count me with you and your scum!
他还活着 对不?
It was a lie, wasn't it?
就像那该死的战争 他还活着
Juste like the whole damn war. It was a lie!
你在说什么?
What are you talkin' about?
那集中营应该是没人的
That camp was supposed to be empty.
蓝波进去 这是个装饰
Rambo goes in, a decorated Vet,
他如没找到 国会就会相信
he finds no POWs, the Congress buys it, case closed.
若他被抓住
And if he happens to get caught
除了你没人知道他还活着
no one knows he's alive except
你就可把这件事抹杀了对不?
you and your computers, and you can reprogram that, can't you?
你以为你在对谁说话?队长
Who the hell do you think you're talkin' to, Trautman?
一个腐败的官僚 他想掩饰臭事
A stinking bureaucrat who's tryin' to cover his ass.
不光是我的问题 这是国家事
No, not just mine,Trautman! We're talkin' about the nation's!
况且你的战士
Besides, it was your hero's fault.
应该是去作什么的
Now if your warrior had gone in,and done what the hell he was supposed to do,
很简单 他应该去拍照的
we'd be out of this clean and simple!He was just supposed to take pictures.
如果那照片上有些什么?
And if those pictures showed something,
是否也会被毁掉
they would have been...lost, wouldn't they?
我想你还是不了解这是怎回事
Oh, Trautman, I still don't think you understand what this is all about.
我知道是为了什么 是为了钱
The same as it always is: money.
在七二年我们应该赔偿五千万战事修复
In '72, we were supposed to pay the Cong 4.5 billion in war reparations.
我们不同意他们就扣留了美军
We reneged, they kept the POWs.
你又在重覆那件事
And you're doing the same thing all over again.
那你会怎么作?
What the hell would you do, Trautman?
拿贿赂去赎自己的人
Pay blackmail money to ransom our own men,
财力支援战力来对抗同盟
and finance the war effort against our allies?
如果一个战俘突然在六点新闻出臭
What if some burnt-out POW shows up on the 6 o'clock news?
你要怎么办?再引起一场战争
What you wanna do?Start the war all over again?
你要报仇而大家高喊着
You wanna bomb Hanoi,wanna everybody screaming
威力进犯?
for armed invasion?
你以为会有参议员像从前一样出来说话
You think civilians are gonna get up on the floor of the United States Senate,
要求数十亿元
and ask for billions of dollars
就为了几个遗忘的鬼魂?
for a couple of forgotten ghosts?
是人 天杀的 是为国家而战的人
Men, goddamn it! Men who fought for their country!
够了
That's enough!
我想把这次谈话给忘了
Trautman...I'm gonna forget this conversation ever took place.
你这混蛋
You bastard!
若我是你
And if I were you,
我不会再回去救他们
I'd never make the mistake of bringing this subject up again!
犯错的是你
You're the one who's making the mistake.
是吗?什么错误
Yeah? What mistake?
蓝波
Rambo.
该死的苏俄混蛋
Damned Russian bastards!
他死定了
He's dead now.
把他带上来
Bring him up!The knife!
这些人真野蛮
These people are so vulgar in their methods.
他们没有同情心
They lack compassion.
我是克洛诺波多夫斯基中尉
I'm Lieutenant-Colonel Podovski.
我还不知道你是谁但我会知道
I do not know who you are yet,but I will!
把他清洗一下
Take him and clean him up.
没事了
That's all.
谢谢你 维特队长
Thank you, Captain Vinh.
请留下一个卫兵
Leave one guard, please.
我看你对痛苦还蛮习惯的
I see you are no stranger to pain.
或许你过去是我的越南同志
Perhaps you have been among my Vietnamese comrades before?
没有回答
No answer?
你要报名字吗?
Do you wish to give your name?
那会有什损失?
What possible harm can that cause?
我可以用一些替代者交换情报员
Pride is a poor substitute for intelligence.
但你一定了解我们必须审问你
What you must understand is that we have to interrogate you.
对这里的某些人来说
To Sergeant Yushin here,
你只是实验的材料
you're piece of meat,a laboratory experiment.
但我们 你也是同志和我一样
But to me, you are a comrade, similar to myself,
我刚被命运所阻止了
just opposed by an act of fate.
我知道你想救出战俘
I know you were trying to facilitate the release of war criminals held
这点我很了解
by this Republic. I can appreciate this.
但你被捕却是很难看的
But this incident, your capture, is......embarrassing.
你一定有解释
We must have explanation.
但首先我想联络你的基地
First of all, I wish you to radio your headquarters,
说你被捕了
and say that you have been captured
罪名是进行间谍活动
and condemned for espionage activities
而且未来不可有同样的事发生
and that no such criminal agression should be attempted in the future!
因为他们会遭遇与你相同的命运
Or they will meet with the same fate as yours.
去你的
Fuck you!
你想充英雄 很好
You wish to test your strength...Good. Good!
用刑
Yushin!
同志 有件东西你可能会有兴趣
Comrade, here is something that might be of interest to you:
这是你们直升机
A transcript of the conversation between
对基地指挥官的对话
your helicopter pilot and his commander we intercepted.
恐龙号 呼叫狼儿
"Dragonfly"... "Wolf's Den"...
名字真富色彩
colorful names!
好了
Here we are:
我们看到他们了
"We have them in sight."
回答是
And the reply:
马上停止行动
"Abort the operation immediately."
这是撤消命令
"This is a recall. Confirm. Over. "
你好像被遗弃了
It seems you were abandoned by direct command.
这些人就是你用痛苦来保护的人
And these are the people you protect...with your pain!
你可以大叫
You may scream.
没什可耻的
There is no shame.
你很强壮 非常强壮
You are strong...Very strong!
目前是如此
The strongest so far.
你过一会你就会死了
But you're nearly dead! Poor waif.
向基地通讯
Make the radio call.
这样简单多了
To talk, to obey would be so much easier.
亚欣要给你一些纪念
Yushin has a memento for you of this occasion!
插入他的眼里
Put it in his eye.
你的生命可能不算什么
If your own life means nothing to you
但他的就不同了
then perhaps his does.
什么都不要说
Don't tell them anything!
你会说的
You will talk.
说啊
Yes?
不要那么作
Don't do it!
说啊!
Do it!
快说
Now!
22056...
Two-two-O-five-six...
狼穴 听到了吗?
Lone Wolf, receive.
这里是一匹狼 22056
This is Lone Wolf, two-two-O-five-six
一匹狼 这里是狼穴
Lone Wolf, this is Wolf's Den.
我们收到了
Transmit location and status. Over.
是什么?
What is it?
是蓝波 长官
It's Rambo, Sir.
我们收到了 你的位置在那儿
We read you, Lone Wolf. What is your position? Over.
我在说一次你的位置在那儿?
I say again: What is your position? Over.
如你不回答 你的朋友死定了
Your friend dies if you do not answer.
约翰 我是翰特 你在那?
Johnny, this is Trautman. Where the hell are you?
约翰 快回答
John, come in!
摩道?
Murdock?
他在这里
He's here.
蓝波 我是摩道 真高兴你活着
Rambo, this is Murdock, we're glad you're alive!
你在那里
Where are you?
把位置告诉我们 我们去救你
Give us your position, and we'll come to pick you up.
摩道
Murdock...
我要去找你
I'm comin' to get you!
这边
This way.
我们目前安全了
We safe for now.
你看来真可怕 蓝波
You look like hell, Rambo.
那不重要
Tough night.
或许你会需要这个
Maybe need this.
- 你受伤了 - 没事
- You hurt bad. - It's alright.
听着
Listen...
你所作的
What you did back there...
我不会忘记的
...I won't forget it.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们现在该怎么办?
What you do now?
尝试到泰国去?
Try to get across to Thailand?
然后去美国
Yeah.Then go America?
你会带我去吗?
You take me with you?
你会吗?
You take me?
我认为你的选择是对的
I think you make good choice.
- 走吗? - 我们走了吧!
- We go? - Let's go.
你还好吗
You alright?
蓝波...
Rambo
你...
You
不会忘了我吧!
...not...forget...me.
我不会的
No.
我要援救小组在一小时候出发
I want the rescue team ready to go in one hour.
你在拿你的安全
You're risking your career,
你的事业及你的家人冒险
your reputation, and even your family's security!
你真的认为一个人值得付出吗?
Do you honestly think any one man's worth all that?
我要命令你撤退
I'm getting you a direct order to withdraw from this project.
你是要给我援助小组
Do I get the rescue team
还是要我自行行动
or do I go over your head?
有件事你似乎不明白这坪我负责
You don't seem to understand something:
你只是工具或是机器
I'm in charge here. You're just a tool.We're the machine.
我要逮捕你 不准你离开这坪
I want him placed under arrest. He's not to leave the base.
他从来没有过机会对不?
He never had a chance, did he?
就像你所说的 中校!
Like you said, Colonel:
他回家去了
He went home.
这里
Yeah! Over here!
赶快
Get back!
搭直升机
C'mon! Go to the chopper! Move, move!Go to the chopper! Go to the chopper!
快
Move!
搭飞机
Go to the chopper!
对了
That's it!
快
Move, move, move!
抓住
Hold on!
快搭上去
C'mon! Move it, move it!
快快
Move, move, move, move!
要走了
A man at the gun!
干了
You guys made it!
是敌机
Chopper on our tail!
要走了  抓稳
Hang on!Hold on!
朝尾部开火
Fire in the tail!
野狼呼叫狼基地
Lone Wolf calling Wolf's Den. Over.Lone Wolf calling Wolf's Den. Over.
狼基地 我是一匹狼你收到吗
Wolf's Den, this is Lone wolf, do you read?
我是野狼 你们收到吗
Wolf's den, this is Lone Wolf, over.
是 我们收到了 一匹野狼
Yes, we hear you, Lone Wolf. Over.
我请求降落
Prepare for emergency landing.
来到的是美国战俘
Arriving with American POWs.
你们听见了 快去迎接
You heard!Prepare for arriving POWs! Let's move!
真高兴你成功了
Glad you made it!
蓝波 我不是下令的人
Rambo, I don't make the orders.
我跟你一样也是服从命令
I take'em, just like you.
我对天发誓 不知会演变成如此
I swear to God I didn't know it was supposed to happen like this.
我只是接受另一项任务
It was just supposed to be another assignment.
任务
Mission...
己完成了
...accomplished!
你从一开始就知道了
You know there's more men out there.
你知道那地方的...
You know where they are.
找回他们了 否则我会再找你
Find'em......or I'll find you!
约翰 你去那里了
John!Where are you going?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想你应该为此而得到几个奖励
You'll get a second Medal of Honor for this.
该给他们 他们才更该得
They should give it to them.They deserve it more.
不能再关你
You can't keep running,
约翰 你现在自由了
John. You're free now.
回我们这里
Come back with us.
回到哪?
Back to what?
我朋友都死了
My friends died here...
我也等于死了
Part of me died here...
一切都是战争造成的
The war, everything that happened here may have been wrong,
别这么恨你的国家
but dammit, don't hate your country for it!
我这就是这一型的人
I'd die for it!
不是你所追求的
Then what is it you want?
我要的...
I want...
也是他们要的
...what they want,
任何家伙来这只是为了付出胆识
and every other guy who came over here,and spilt his guts
他付出了他的一切
and gave everything he had, wants...
我们为了国家 国家也要爱我们
...for our country to love us...
就如我们爱他一样
...as much as WE love it.
我要的就是这一些
That's what I want.
你要以何为生
How will you live, John?
过一天是一天
Day by day.